Hello friends, today in this video we will
talk about the business loan of Cholamandalam company. We will know that
if you want to take loan from Chola Madam for business, then
what documents are required for it, what
rate of interest can you get, what will be the
eligibility criteria on the basis of which the
selection will be made and what
charges can be levied on you and a very important
point I would like to tell you that
you should watch this video completely because in the end of this video
I am going to tell you a very
important thing in the 16th part, so let's
start this video quickly, first of all let's
talk about the performance required in the business,
if your
form is properly registered then the
documents required for it are PAN card and Aadhar card of the
applicant and copyligion along with the Gumasta of the form,
GST certificate if applicable
and you will also need Udyam certificate,
after that latest T&W ID along with 6
months bank statement and latest one
year GST return can also be levied on you
and along with that very important document  There is
one more and that is owner. If you own your house or
your shop or any commercial
premises where a businessman does business, then
you will have to provide its
ownership proof, be it the
electricity bill which is in your name or in the name of any
member of your family, along with a
copy of the certificate, you have the power to provide it
if your name is not on the electricity bill,
or you can also provide its tax,
if it is a partnership firm, then it will require the
PAN card of the company along with the
PAN card of all the partners, Aadhar card,
after that the company's Gumasta, its
partnership certificate and GST certificate if
applicable and you can also provide the Udyam certificate,
after that you will require the latest 2
years ITR of the company along with 6 months
bank statement of the company and the
latest one year GST return if you are
GST applicable, and along with it the ownership
proof which is if any one of the partners owns a house
or any commercial one, then you will need its ownership
proof, if any form is private
limited, then you will need the
PAN card of the company along with the document attached to it.  It
means Memorandum of Association
and AAVE means Article of Organization, you will have to
provide this, after that you can
send your ITR of the company for the latest two years,
along with 6 months bank
statement of the company, it will be required and
you will also have to provide PAN card and Aadhar card of all the directors of the company
and latest one year GST return if the
company is GST applicable and
lastly, that is, the most important
document is the ownership proof, which can be accepted even if any one
director's group is given, so
this was the list of documents for
proprietorship partnership and private
limited company, now we will talk about
eligibility, while taking a bus from 16 Mandal, the
most important
parameter for you is your civil score, it should be
minimum 675 plus, yes,
if your friend score means Civics is also 675 plus, then
you become eligible to take a
loan from Chola Madam, along with all
your ongoing loan tracks, whether
you have a business running or a home loan, all of them  It should be
absolutely regular, there should
not be any kind of EMI return in it,
after that your bank balance should be
properly maintained,
this is a very important
parameter on the basis of which
loan is given to you on calculation basis,
if you are GST applicable then your
GST return should be properly paid,
along with that your
income tax return should also be regularly paid, there should
not be any EMI return of your loan in the last six months, if there is
one hand of our return before that then it will be
accepted but there should not be any
EMI return of any kind in the last six months
and your business
profile should be positive, you should not have
any negative profile, just like
you know if you are running a construction company
or you are in any other type of business
like labour contractor and
you do business in all other things, then it can come
in the negative profile and the vintage of your business
profile means the
date of starting your business should be
3 years old, that is, your
business  The window should be 3 years old.
Ownership proof is compulsory in this, meaning
your loan on the property should be compulsory. It should be
residential loan and commercial loan is also movable,
but ownership proof is compulsory.
If you have a CC or OID account, then the
utilization of your credit limit should not be more than 90% or 95%. It should be
properly utilized. This is
also a very important point for
legibility calculation while taking business from Cholamandalam. And the last is
that your resident or your
commercial property from where you are
doing your business should be
within the geo limit of Cholamandalam branch
because their branch should be there till there.
Your resident and your commercial should be within their geo limit area.
This is also a very important condition on the
basis of which you are given loan in the business.
Now let us talk about the rate of
interest, so generally Cholamandalam's loan is from
18% to 21%.  The rate of interest it
provides you will be based on
your loan amount. The larger your loan
amount, the more
your rate of interest will depend on it.
You can get it from Chola Madam from the 18th to the 21st or 22nd,
and the tenure can range from 3
to 5 years, with a maximum of 5 years. They
can provide you with a large business loan. Right now, we are
talking about charges, so the charge is 2% plus
GST, which will be Cholamandalam's processing
fee. After that, the insurance,
loan tax, insurance, at least, can be around 1-2%.
These are the basic Cholamandalam
business loan charges, which you must take
care of. One important point I would
like to tell you about Chola Madam's loan, which
I said in the beginning of this video, that in
this video I will tell you a
very important point about Cholamandalam's loan, that is,
Chola Mandalam provides
term loans as well as overdrafts.  It
also provides a top-line facility,
which is available for at least 5 years, a maximum of 5
years. Similarly,
Bajaj's top-line facility, which is for 4 years, offers a
drop-line facility. Its
charges are approximately ₹100 crore, but the
interest rate is 1% higher than a term loan. This
means that if you
take a terminal loan and
your interest rate is 18%, then
in overdraft it can go up to 19% annually. So,
you must keep this in mind.
This is very important. The facilities
it provides in Cholamandalam are: These were
some important things that I tried to explain in
this video about Chola Mandalam's business loans.
If you want to
know anything else,
I've provided an email ID in the description, along with a
WhatsApp link. You
can message or email me. I or
my team will definitely contact you. So,
such informative information  Subscribe to my channel to watch videos
and keep watching
assets